闪  灵
根据
史蒂芬·金小说改编
制片人/导演
斯坦利·库布里克
面  试
你好  我和乌尔曼先生有预约
Hi. I've got an appointment with Mr. Ullman.
我叫杰克·托伦斯
My name is Jack Torrance.
他的办公室是左手边第一间
His office is the first door on the left.
谢谢
Thank you.
-乌尔曼先生  -正是
- Mr. Ullman? - Yes.
-我是杰克·托伦斯  -快请进  杰克
- I'm Jack Torrance. - Oh, come on in, Jack.
很高兴认识你
Very nice to meet you.
我也很高兴认识你  乌尔曼先生
Nice to meet you too, Mr. Ullman.
-这是我的秘书  苏希  -你好
- This is my secretary, Susie. - Hello.
-苏希  你好  -我们这里难找吗
- Susie, how do you do? - Any trouble finding us?
一点不难找  我三个半小时就到了
No problem at all. I made the trip in 3 and a half hours.
那真是算很快了
That's very good time.
快请坐吧  杰克
Sit down a minute, Jack.
在这千万别拘束
Just make yourself at home.
要来杯咖啡吗
Would you like some coffee?
如果有的话  就来点吧  谢谢
If you're having some, I wouldn't mind. Thanks.
-苏希  -好
- Susie. - Sure.
去叫比尔·沃森来跟我们一起
And would you ask Bill Watson to join us.
好的  我这就去
Yes, I will.
妈妈
Mom?
怎么了
Yeah?
你真的想去住在那个酒店里过冬天吗
Do you really want to go and live in that hotel for the winter?
当然了
Sure I do.
肯定很好玩
It'll be lots of fun.
好吧  应该是吧
Yeah. I guess so.
反正  这里也没什么人一起玩
Anyway, there's hardly anybody to play with around here.
我知道  结交新朋友总是需要花些时间的
I know. It always takes a little time to make new friends.
是啊  或许是吧
Yeah, I guess so.
托尼呢
What about Tony?
我猜他肯定很期待去酒店
He's looking forward to the hotel, I bet.
不  我才不呢  托伦斯夫人
No, I ain't, Mrs. Torrance.
拜托  托尼  别犯傻了
Now, come on, Tony. Don't be silly.
我不想去那里  托伦斯夫人
I don't want to go there, Mrs. Torrance.
你为什么不想去呢
How come you don't want to go?
我就是不想去
I just don't.
那我们就走着瞧吧
Let's just wait and see.
我们都会玩得很开心的
We're all going to have a real good time.
比尔  我想介绍你认识一下杰克·托伦斯
Bill, I'd like you to meet Jack Torrance.
-你好  比尔  -你好
- How do you do, Bill? - How do you do.
-很高兴认识你  -很高兴认识你
- Nice to meet you. - Pleasure to meet you.
坐吧  比尔  一起聊聊
Grab a chair, Bill. Join in.
杰克今年冬天会帮我们照看眺望酒店
Jack is going to take care of the Overlook for us this winter.
等我们谈完  希望你带他四处转转
I'd like you to take him around place soon as we're through.
好的
Fine.
杰克是学校里的老师
Jack is a schoolteacher.
以前是老师
Uh, formerly a schoolteacher.
你现在做什么工作
What line of work are you in now?
我是个作家
I'm a writer.
教书差不多就是为了糊口而已
Teaching's been more or less a way of making ends meet.
如今这样对你来说应该是个很大的变化
This ought to be quite a change for you.
我很期待有变化
Well, I'm looking for a change.
我们在丹佛的人强烈推荐杰克
Our people in Denver recommended Jack very highly,
这一次
and for once...
我同意他们说的
I agree with them.
刚刚说到哪了
Let's see, where were we?
我刚刚  准备给你解释
I was ,yeah, about to explain...
我们的营业季是从5月15号到10月30号
that our season here runs from may 15th to October 30th.
然后彻底停业  到第二年的5月再开业
Then we close down completely until the following May.
我能问问为什么吗
Do you mind if I ask why you do that?
在我看来在这里滑雪应该会很棒
It seems to me that the skiing up here would be fantastic.
的确是的  问题在于要花费巨大的成本
It would be. The problem is the enormous cost...
维持到萨德温德镇的路面能够通行
it would be to keep the road to Sidewinder open.
那是段25英里的路
It's a 25-mile stretch of road.
冬天的降雪厚度能有20英尺
It gets 20 feet of snow during the winter.
要保持路面畅通  从经济上来看是完全不划算的
There's just no way to make it economically feasible to keep it clear.
1907年建这个地方的时候
When the place was built in 1907...
人们对冬季运动尚不感兴趣
there was very little interest in winter sports.
选择这里完全是看中其幽静的环境和美丽的风景
This site was chosen for its seclusion and scenic beauty.
这里的确够幽静和美丽的
It's certainly got plenty of that.
没错
That's right.
在丹佛时  他们有没有告诉你
Did they give you any idea in Denver...
这份工作具体是做什么的
about what the job entails?
就大致说了一下
Only in a very general way.
冬季真的会无比残酷
The winters can be fantastically cruel.
基本就是要应对高额的损坏
The basic idea is to cope with the very costly damage...
以及可能出现的折旧
and depreciation which can occur.
这主要包括烧锅炉
This consists mainly of running the boiler...
每天例行给酒店的不同区域供暖
heating different parts of the hotel on a daily rotating basis...
出现损坏及时修理
repairing damage as it occurs...
及时修理小毛病就不会变成大问题
and doing repairs so the elements can't get a foothold.
我觉得没有问题
That sounds fine to me.
从体力上说  这份工作要求不高
Physically, it's not a very demanding job.
在冬天  唯一一件
The only thing that can
可能会有点难熬的事情
get a bit trying here during the winter...
就是会有强烈的孤独感
is a tremendous sense of isolation.
那恰恰就是我想寻求的
Well, that just happens to be exactly what I'm looking for.
我正在写新作品的大纲
I'm outlining a new writing project.
五个月宁静的时光正是我想要的
And, five months of peace is just what I want.
那很好  杰克
That's very good, Jack.
因为  对有的人来说
Because, for some people...
孤独  与世隔绝
solitude ...and isolation...
本身  就会成为问题
can, of itself, become a problem.
我不会
Not for me.
你夫人和儿子呢
How about your wife and son?
你觉得他们能接受吗
Do you think they'll take to it?
他们会很喜欢的
They'll love it.
好极了
Great.
在我把你交接给比尔之前
Well, before I turn you over to Bill,
我觉得还有一件事我们需要聊聊
there's one other thing I think we should talk about.
我也不想耸人听闻
I don't want to sound melodramatic,
但是这件事的确会让有些人
but it's something been known to give a few people
犹豫到底要不要接受这份工作
second thoughts about the job.
我很有兴趣知道
I'm intrigued.
我觉得在丹佛时他们应该没告诉你
I don't suppose they tell you anything in Denver
1970年冬天发生在这里的一起悲剧事件
about the tragedy we had up here during the winter of 1970.
他们似乎的确没说
I don't believe they did.
我这个职位的前任负责人
My predecessor in this job
雇了一个叫查尔斯·格拉迪的人当冬季管理员
hired a man named Charles Grady as the winter caretaker.
他是带着夫人和两个女儿一起来的
He came up with his wife and two little girls
一个8岁  一个10岁
of about 8 and 10.
他过去的工作记录很好
He had a good employment record,
推荐信都对他赞不绝口
good references.
据我所知道的信息
And from what I've been told,
他似乎是一个非常正常的人
he seemed like a completely normal individual.
但是在冬天的某个时候
But at some point during the winter
他一定是经受了
he must have suffered
某种程度上的精神崩溃
some kind of a complete mental breakdown.
他发狂了  然后...
He ran amuck and...
用一把斧子杀了全家人
killed his family with an ax.
把他们整齐地码在西翼的一个房间里  然后他...
Stacked them neatly in a room in the west wing, and then he...
他把双管猎枪对准了嘴里  举枪自尽了
he put both barrels of his shotgun in his mouth.
警方...
The police...
警方认为这就是人们以前常说的幽闭症
they thought that it was what the old-timers used to call cabin fever.
这种幽闭恐惧反应可能会出现在
A kind of claustrophobic reaction which can occur
一群人被困在一起很长时间之后
when people are shut in together over long periods of time.
那还真是...
That is...
相当离奇的故事
quite a story.
是啊  的确
Yeah, it is.
我还是很难相信这事真的是在这里发生的
It's still hard for me to believe it actually happened here.
但事实如此
But it did.
然后
And, uh
我觉得你应该能理解我为什么要告诉你
I think you can appreciate why I wanted to tell you about it.
我当然理解
I certainly can.
我也理解为什么你在丹佛的那些手下
I also understand why your people in Denver
把这事留给你来亲自告诉我
left it for you to tell me.
显然  有些人一想到
Obviously, some people can be put off
要在发生过这种事的地方
by the idea of staying alone in a place
单独待这么久的时间  的确会打退堂鼓
where something like that actually happened.
你大可安心  乌尔曼先生
Well, you can rest assured Mr. Ullman,
我不会打退堂鼓的
that's not going to happen with me.
至于我夫人那边
And as far as my wife is concerned
我相信等我告诉她  她会被深深地吸引住
I'm sure she'll be absolutely fascinated when I tell her.
她是个忠实的鬼故事  恐怖电影爱好者
She's a confirmed ghost story and horror film addict.
托尼  你觉得爸爸能拿到这份工作吗
Tony, do you think dad'll get the job?
他已经拿到了
He already did.
几分钟后他就要打给温蒂告诉她了
He's going to phone Wendy up in a few minutes to tell her.
喂
Hello.
-嗨  宝贝  -嗨  亲爱的  还顺利吗
- Hi, babe. - Hi, hon. How's it going?
好极了  我还在酒店里
Great. Look, I'm at the hotel
接下来有一堆事情要去做
and I still have a awful lot to go through.
我觉得我9点甚至10点前是到不了家了
I don't think I can get home before 9:00 or 10:00.
听起来你已经得到这份工作了
Sounds like you got the job.
没错  这地方很美
Right. It's a beautiful place.
你和丹尼肯定会喜欢的
You and Danny are going to love it.
托尼  你为什么不想去那家酒店
Tony, why don't you want to go to the hotel?
我不知道
I don't know.
你肯定知道  快点告诉我
You do too know. Now come on, tell me.
我不想说
I don't want to.
拜托啦
Please.
不
No.
托尼  告诉我
Now, Tony, tell me.
现在把眼睛睁开让我看看
Now, hold your eyes still so I can see.
很好  另一只
That's good. Now the other one.
好孩子
Good boy.
丹尼
Now, Danny
你记不记得在刷牙的时候
when you were brushing your teeth
闻到什么奇怪的气味
do you remember if you smelled anything funny
或者看到什么强烈的闪光
or saw any bright, flashing lights
或是任何奇怪的东西
or anything at all strange?
没有
No.
你还记得你之前在刷牙吗
Do you remember when you were brushing your teeth?
记得
Yes.
刷牙之后紧接着发生的事  你还记得什么
What's the next thing you remember after you were brushing your teeth?
我妈妈在说  "醒醒  醒醒  丹尼  醒醒"
My mom was saying, "Wake up. Wake up, Danny, wake up. "
丹尼  你还记不记得
Now, Danny, can you remember what you were doing
在开始刷牙之前你在做什么
just before you started brushing your teeth?
和托尼说话
Talking to Tony.
托尼是你的宠物吗
Is Tony one of your animals?
不  他是住在我嘴里的小男孩
No. He's a little boy that lives in my mouth.
托尼是他的幻想好友
Tony's his imaginary friend.
你现在能不能张开嘴  让我见见托尼
If you were to open your mouth now, could I see Tony?
不行
No.
为什么
Why not?
因为他藏起来了
Because he hides.
他去哪了
Where does he go?
进我肚子里了
To my stomach.
托尼让你做过什么事吗
Does Tony ever tell you to do things?
我不想再聊托尼了
I don't want to talk about Tony anymore.
好吧
Okay.
没关系
That's fine.
好了  丹尼
All right, Danny.
我想请你帮我个忙
I'm going to ask you to do me a favor
今天都乖乖地躺在床上  好吗
and stay quietly in bed for the rest of the day. Okay?
一定要这样吗
Do I have to?
是的  我希望你听话
Yes. I'd like you to.
我们去另一个房间聊一会儿
We're going in the other room for a few minutes and talk.
我会回来看你的
I'll come back and check on you.
-好吗  -好的
-Okay?  - Okay.
再见
Bye.
-我们到客厅去吧  -好的
- Shall we go into the living room? - Yes.
-请坐  -谢谢
- Please. - Thank you.
托伦斯夫人  我觉得你无需担心
Mrs. Torrance, I don't think you have anything to worry about.
我非常肯定丹尼的身体没有任何问题
I'm quite sure there's nothing physically wrong with Danny.
是吗
Yeah?
他现在看上去没有任何问题
He seems absolutely fine now.
但你真该看看他之前的样子
But you should've seen him.
我懂的
I know.
小孩出点事能把做父母的吓死
Kids can scare you to death.
但相信我  这种突然的发作一点也不罕见
But believe me, these episodes are not at all uncommon.
虽然看起来很糟  但实际情况并非如此
And they look much worse than they are.
不过他到底是怎么回事
But what was the matter with him?
托伦斯夫人  很多时候
Mrs. Torrance, Most of the time,
孩子的这种突然发作都无法解释
these episodes with kids are never explained.
通常是由情感因素引起的  很少会再次出现
They're brought on by emotional factors and rarely occur again.
那更像是自我催眠
They're more akin to autohypnosis
一种自发式的催眠行为
A kind of self-induced trance.
如果再发生  尽管我觉得不大可能
If it reoccurs, which I doubt
可以考虑做一些检查
we can always think about having some tests done.
不了  谢谢你
No, thank you.
我相信你说得对
I'm sure you're right.
你在博尔德待了很久吗  托伦斯夫人
Have you been in Boulder long, Mrs. Torrance?
刚来大约三个月
Only about three months.
我们是从佛蒙特州来的  我丈夫以前在那教书
We're from Vermont. My husband was teaching school there.
丹尼那位幻想好友的出现...
Did the appearance of Danny's imaginary friend...
托尼
Tony.
托尼的初次出现
Did Tony's first appearance
是否恰好是你们搬来这里的时候
happen to coincide with your arrival here?
不是
No.
我想想...
Let's see...
我想丹尼开始跟托尼说话
I guess Danny started talking to Tony
大约是在我们送他进幼儿园的时候
about the time we put him in nursery school.
他对于学校生活适应得好吗
Did he adjust well to school?
不好
No.
起先他不太喜欢上学
He didn't like it too much at first.
然后他受了伤  所以我们有阵子没让他去上学
Then he had an injury, so we kept him out for a while and
没错  差不多就是那时候
Yeah, I guess that's about
我发现他在跟托尼说话的
when I first noticed he was talking to Tony.
他受了什么伤
What sort of injury did he have?
他的肩膀脱臼了
He dislocated his shoulder.
怎么弄的
How did he manage to do that?
就是小孩子常见的那种情况  你懂的
It was just one of those things, you know.
纯粹是意外
Purely an accident.
我丈夫一直在酗酒
My husband had been drinking and
他那天晚回来三个多小时
he came home about three hours late.
那晚他心情不太好
So he wasn't exactly in the greatest mood that night.
丹尼把书本和作业纸弄得满屋子都是
And Danny had scattered some of his school papers all over the room
我丈夫抓住他的胳膊  把他拉开
and my husband grabbed his arm to pull him away from them.
就是父母常会对小孩做的那种事
It's just the sort of thing you do 100 times with a child
在公园里  或街上  都很常见
you know, in a park or in the street.
但那一次
But on this particular occasion
我丈夫用力过猛
my husband just used too much strength
伤到了丹尼的胳膊
and he injured Danny's arm.
不过  这事还是有些好处的
Anyway, something good did come out of it all
因为他说
because he said:
"温蒂  我再也不会喝一滴酒了
"Wendy, I'm never going to touch another drop.
如果我再喝  你就离开我"
And if I do, you can leave me. "
然后他就再没喝过酒了
And he didn't.
他五个月没有沾酒了
He hasn't had any alcohol in 5 months.
停  业  日
天呐
Boy.
我们一定在很高的地方  空气都感觉很不同
We must really be high up. The air feels so different.
爸爸
Dad?
什么事
Yes?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
你应该吃早餐的
You should've eaten your breakfast.
等到了酒店我就给你弄东西吃  好吗
We'll get you something as soon as we get to the hotel. Okay?
好吧  妈妈
Okay, Mom.
唐纳大队不就是在这里被雪困住的吗
Wasn't it around here that the Donner party got snowbound?
我觉得应该是更靠西的地方  在内华达山脉
I think that was farther west, in the Sierras.
什么是唐纳大队
What was the Donner party?
是西部大开发时期的一群移民
They were a party of settlers in covered wagon times.
有年冬天  他们被大雪困在了大山里
They got snowbound one winter in the mountains.
为了活命  他们不得不靠吃人肉为生
They had to resort to cannibalism in order to stay alive.
你是说他们把自己人给吃了
You mean they ate each other up?
只有这样才能生存下来
They had to in order to survive.
杰克
Jack.
别担心  妈妈
Don't worry, Mom.
我知道关于食人的事  我在电视上看过
I know all about cannibalism. I saw it on TV.
瞧吧  没事的
See, it's okay.
他在电视上看过
He saw it on the television.
-飞机什么时候起飞  -8点半
- What time does the plane leave? - 8:30.
那我们还有足够的时间把各项事宜再过一遍
That gives us plenty of time to go over everything first.
-再见  乌尔曼先生  -再见
- Goodbye, Mr. Ullman. - Bye.
早上好  杰克  希望没让你等太久
Good morning, Jack. I hope you haven't been waiting too long.
没关系  刚好让我们有时间吃点东西
No problem. In fact we had time to grab a bite to eat.
那就好  很高兴你们在厨房关停前赶到了
Good. Glad you made it before they shut down the kitchen.
-你好  -你的家人到处看过了吗
- Hi. - Is your family having a look around?
没有  我儿子发现了游戏室
No, my son's discovered the games room.
-行李都拿进来了吧  -就在那边
- Has your luggage been brought in? - Right there.
好的
Oh, fine.
鉴于我们今天要带你了解不少地方
In view of all the ground we have to cover today
我建议我们先快速看一下你们的公寓
I suggest we have a quick look at your apartment
然后立刻开始
and get started straight away.
比尔  你能安排先把托伦斯一家的东西
Bill, would you have the Torrances' things
送到他们的公寓去吗
brought to their apartment.
-好的  -我最好先叫一下我的家人
- Fine. - I'd better collect my family first.
好的
Oh, yes.
这里是我们的科罗拉多休闲室
This is our Colorado Lounge.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
我的天啊
My God!
这里真是美极了  不是吗  亲爱的
This place is fantastic, isn't it, hon?
当然
It sure is.
我从没见过这样的东西
I've never seen anything like this before.
这些印第安风格的设计都是真品吗
Are all these Indian designs authentic?
好像主要是根据纳瓦霍族和阿帕切族的图案设计的
I believe they're based mainly on Navajo and Apache motifs.
真的太美了
They're really gorgeous.
实际上
As a matter of fact
这可能是我见过的最美的酒店了
this is probably the most gorgeous hotel I've ever seen.
这家老酒店有着辉煌的历史
This old place has had an illustrious past.
在其全盛时期  曾住满了社会名流
In its heyday, it was one of the stopping place for the jet setters
即便那时大家都还不知道社会名流是什么意思
even before anybody knew what a jet set was.
有四位总统曾在此住过
We had four presidents who stayed here.
很多电影明星
Lots of movie stars.
有皇室的人吗
Royalty?
都是最上层的人物
All the best people.
这里是酒店的员工宿舍侧楼
This is the staff wing of the hotel.
其它卧室冬天都不供暖
None of the other bedrooms are heated during the winter.
-再见  乌尔曼先生  -再见  姑娘们
- Goodbye, Mr. Ullman. - Goodbye, girls.
这就是你们的住处
And here are your quarters.
起居室  卧室  洗手间
Living room, bedroom, bathroom.
还有给你们的儿子住的小房间
And a small bedroom for your son.
非常适合小孩子
Perfect for a child.
-是啊  -是的
- Yeah. - Yes.
好了  这房子独门独户  不用跟别人共用设施
Well, then. Place is very nicely self-contained.
也好打理
Easy to keep.
舒适
Cozy.
是的  非常适合一家人居住
Yes, very cozy for a family.
如果你们想换个环境
If you feel like spreading out
酒店的其他地方也随便你们住
you have the rest of the hotel to move around in.
这里真是...
Well, it's very...
太有家的感觉了
homey.
是啊
Yeah.
这里是我们著名的树篱迷宫
This is our famous hedge maze.
算是这里的一处独特景点吧  墙有13英尺高
It's quite an attraction here. The walls are 13 feet high
树篱和酒店一样历史悠久
and the hedge is as old as the hotel itself.
很好玩
A lot of fun,
但我一般是不会进去的
but I wouldn't want to go in there
除非我有一小时的空闲时间用来找出路
unless I had an hour to spare to find my way out.
眺望酒店是什么时候建成的
When was the Overlook built?
1907年开始建造
Construction started in 1907.
1909年完工
It was finished in 1909.
这里曾经是一座印第安坟场
The site's supposed to be on an Indian burial ground.
据我所知  他们在施工时
And I believe they actually had to repel
不得不打退几次印第安人的袭击
a few Indian attacks as they were building it.
那是我们的雪地车
That's our Snowcat.
你们都会开车吗
Can you both drive a car?
会
Yes.
那就好
That's fine.
因为驾驶雪地车基本和开车一样
Because basically the Snowcat operates very much like a car.
很快就能掌握诀窍了
It won't take you long to get the hang of it.
事实上
As a matter of fact,
我们去年从芝加哥请了一位设计师
we brought a decorator in from Chicago just last year
给酒店的这一部分进行重新装修
to refurbish this part of the hotel.
他确实装修得很不错
He sure did a beautiful job.
粉色和金色是我最喜欢的颜色
Pink and gold are my favorite colors.
这里是我们的金色舞厅
Well, this is our Gold Ballroom.
我就说嘛
I'll say!
这里可以轻松容纳三百人
We can accommodate up to 300 people here very comfortably.
天呐  我们可以在这里办一场盛大的派对
Boy, I bet you we could really have a good party in this room.
恐怕你们办不起来多么盛大的派对
I'm afraid you won't do too well here
除非你们能自带物资
unless you brought supplies.
我们停业时  会将酒全部撤走
We always remove the booze from the premises when we shut down.
那可以减少我们通常得承担的保险费用
That reduces the insurance we normally have to carry.
我们不喝酒
We don't drink.
那你们走运了
Then you're in luck.
迪克  快过来跟托伦斯夫妇打个招呼
Dick, come on over and say hello to Mr. and Mrs. Torrance.
这位是迪克·哈洛兰  我们的主厨
This is Dick Hallorann, our head chef.
-哈洛兰先生  我是杰克  -很高兴认识你  杰克
- Mr. Hallorann, I'm Jack. - Glad to meet you, Jack.
这位是我妻子  温妮芙德
This is my wife, Winifred.
-很高兴认识你  温妮芙德  -很高兴认识你
- Glad to meet you, Winifred. - Nice to meet you.
托伦斯夫妇今年冬天会替我们照料眺望酒店
The Torrances are gonna take care of the Overlook for us this winter.
太好了  你们目前觉得这个酒店怎么样
That's just great. How do you folks like our hotel so far?
简直棒极了
It's just wonderful.
嗨  丹尼
Hi, Danny!
我发现他在外面找你们
I found him outside looking for you.
丹  你厌倦轰炸宇宙了吗
Dan, did you get tired of bombing the universe?
是的
Yeah.
过来
Come on over here.
-谢谢  -谢谢你  苏希
- Thanks. - Thank you, Susie.
迪克  如果你准备好了
Dick, if you're ready to do it now,
我觉得你可以带托伦斯夫人去看看厨房
I think it'd be a good idea if you could show Mrs. Torrance the kitchen
我再继续跟杰克交代交代
while I continue on with Jack.
非常乐意  这边请  托伦斯夫人
It would be a pleasure. Right this way, Mrs. Torrance.
太棒了  待会儿见  亲爱的
Great. See you later, hon.
回见  亲爱的
Bye, darling.
安全出口  不得堵塞
托伦斯夫人  你丈夫介绍你时  叫你温妮芙德
Mrs. Torrance, your husband introduced you as Winifred.
那我应该叫你温妮还是芙莱蒂
Now, are you a "Winnie," or a "Freddie"?
叫我温蒂就行
I'm a Wendy.
温蒂啊  真好听  再好听不过了
Oh, Wendy. That's nice. That's the prettiest.
天啊  这厨房太气派了
God, this is the kitchen, huh?
没错  正是
Yeah, this is it.
你觉得怎么样  丹尼  够大吗
How do you like it, Danny? Is it big enough for you?
是的  这是我见过的最大的地方
Yeah. It's the biggest place I ever seen.
是啊  这里简直就是一个巨大的迷宫
Yeah, this whole place is such an enormous maze.
我觉得每次进来这儿
I feel like I'll have to
都得撒面包屑  标记返回的路
leave a trail of breadcrumbs every time I come in.
别灰心  托伦斯夫人
Don't let it get you down, Mrs. Torrance.
这里是很大  但也不过是个厨房而已
It's big, but it still ain't nothing but a kitchen.
而且这里的很多东西你连碰都不用碰
And a lot of this stuff you'll never have to touch.
就算真让我碰  我也不知道怎么用
I wouldn't know what to do with it if I did.
至少你们丝毫不用担心食物的问题
Well, one thing for sure, you don't have to worry about food.
因为你们一家可以在这里吃上一整年
because ou folks could eat up here a whole year
菜单都不带重样的
and never have the same menu twice.
这里是我们的步入式冷冻室
Now, right here is our walk-in freezer.
我们将所有肉类都储存在这里
Now, this is where we keep all of our meat.
15扇肋排
You got 15 rib roasts...
30袋汉堡肉  每袋重10磅
30 ten-pound bags of hamburger.
12只火鸡  大概40只鸡
We got 12 turkeys, about 40 chickens...
50块西冷牛排  24卷猪排
50 sirloin steaks, two dozen of pork roast...
还有20只羊腿  你喜欢羊肉吗  博士
and 20 legs of lamb. Do you like lamb, Doc?
-不喜欢  -不喜欢吗
- No. - You don't?
那你最喜欢吃什么
Well, what's your favorite food, then?
炸薯条配番茄酱
French fries and ketchup.
那也没问题  博士
Well, I think we can manage that too, Doc.
跟我来  小心脚下
Come along, now. Watch your step.
哈洛兰先生
Mr. Hallorann...
你怎么知道我们叫他博士
how'd you know we call him Doc?
你说什么
Beg your pardon?
「博士」  你刚才两次那样叫丹尼
Doc. You called Danny "Doc" twice just now.
-是吗  -是啊
- I did? - Yeah.
我们有时候叫他博士
We call him Doc sometimes,
就像兔八哥卡通片里的博士
like in the Bugs Bunny cartoons.
但你是怎么知道的
But how did you know that?
我想可能是因为我听见你那样叫过他吧
Well, I guess I probably heard you call him that.
有可能  但我真不记得
Well, it's possible. But I honestly don't remember
我们见面之后  我那样叫过他
calling him that since we've been with you.
他看起来就像个博士  对不对
Well, anyway, he looks like a Doc, doesn't he?
「还好吗  博士」
What's up, Doc?
好了  这里是储藏室
Now, this is the storeroom.
托伦斯夫人  在这里面
In here, Mrs. Torrance,
存放着我们所有的干货和罐头
is where we keep all the dried goods and the canned goods.
有水果罐头  蔬菜罐头
We got canned fruits and vegetables...
鱼罐头  肉罐头  各种冷吃热吃麦片
canned fish and meats, hot and cold cereals.
博斯特麦片  玉米片  膨化甜麦片
Post Toasties, Corn Flakes, Sugar Puffs...
脆米麦片  燕麦片  脆小麦麦片  还有麦乳
Rice Krispies, oatmeal, Wheatena and Cream of Wheat.
几十罐黑糖蜜
You got a dozen jugs of black molasses.
60盒奶粉
We got 60 boxes of dried milk...
你想吃冰激凌吗  博士
How'd you like some ice cream, Doc?
饼干  手指卷面包
Sociables, finger rolls...
还有七种其他的
and 7 kinds of what have you.
有桃干  杏干
Now, we've got dried peaches, dried apricots...
葡萄干还有西梅干
dried raisins and dried prunes.
托伦斯夫人
You know, Mrs. Torrance,
想过得快乐  就得保持日常生活细节不变
you got to keep regular if you want to be happy.
-参观得怎么样  -很好
- How're you getting on? - Just fine.
迪克  能让托伦斯夫人跟我们来一下吗
Dick, can we borrow Mrs. Torrance for a few minutes?
我们正要去地下室
We're on our way through to the basement.
我保证不会很久的
I promise we won't keep her very long.
没问题  乌尔曼先生  我们正要去吃冰激凌
No problem, Mr. Ullman. I was just getting to the ice cream.
-你喜欢冰激凌吧  博士  -喜欢
- You like ice cream, Doc? - Yeah.
我想也是
I thought you did.
你们不介意
You folks don't mind
我带丹尼吃点冰激凌  边吃边等你们吧
if I give Danny some ice cream while we waiting for you?
-当然不  -不介意
- Not at all. - No, we don't mind.
-好  -你觉得好不好  博士
- Good. - Sound good to you, Doc?
-好  -好  你要乖乖的哦
- Yeah. - Okay, you behave yourself.
你喜欢什么冰激凌  博士
What kind of ice cream do you like, Doc?
巧克力的
Chocolate.
那我们就吃巧克力口味的  来吧  孩子
Chocolate it shall be. Come on, son.
今天大家似乎都很忙乱啊
It's amazing, how much activities going on today.
是啊  昨天客人们还有一些员工离开了
Yes. Well, the guests and some of the staff left yesterday,
但停业前最后一天总是很忙乱
but the last day's always hectic.
大家都想尽早上路离开
Everybody wants to be on their way as early as possible.
等到今晚5点  就像没人在这里存在过一样
By 5 o'clock tonight, you'll never know anybody was ever here.
-就像一艘幽灵船  -没错
- Just like a ghost ship, huh? - Yes.
你知道我是怎么知道你叫"博士"的吗
Do you know how I knew your name was Doc?
你知道我在说什么  对吧
You know what I'm talking about, don't you?
我记得  我小时候
I can remember when I was a little boy,
我奶奶和我全程不张嘴
my grandmother and I could hold conversations
就可以进行对话
entirely without ever opening our mouths.
她称之为「闪灵」能力
She called it "Shining."
很久以来  我以为
And for a long time I thought
只有我们祖孙俩有这种能力
it was just the two of us that had "the Shine" to us.
就像你可能以为只有你一个人有一样
Just like you probably thought you was the only one.
但其实还有别人
But there are other folks,
虽然他们自己不知道  或者不相信
though mostly they don't know it, or don't believe it.
你从什么时候开始有这能力的
How long have you been able to do it?
你为什么不想说呢
Why don't you want to talk about it?
我不应该说出来
I'm not supposed to.
谁说你不应该说出来
Who says you ain't supposed to?
托尼
Tony.
托尼是谁
Who's Tony?
托尼是住在我嘴里的小男孩
Tony's the little boy that lives in my mouth.
是托尼告诉你一些事的吗
Is Tony the one that tells you things?
是的
Yes.
他是怎么告诉你那些事的
How does he tell you things?
就好像我睡着以后  他给我看一些东西
It's like I go to sleep, and he shows me things.
但等我醒来  我什么都记不得了
But when I wake up, I can't remember everything.
你爸妈知道托尼的存在吗
Does your mom and dad know about Tony?
知道
Yes.
他们知道他会告诉你一些事吗
Do they know he tells you things?
托尼告诉我  千万别告诉他们
Tony told me never to tell them.
托尼跟你说过关于这里的一些事吗
Has Tony ever told you anything about this place?
关于眺望酒店
About the Overlook Hotel?
我不知道
I don't know.
好好想想  博士
Now think real hard, Doc.
想想
Think.
也许他给我看过一点
Maybe he showed me something.
努力想想是什么
Try to think of what it was.
哈洛兰先生  你怕这里吗
Mr. Hallorann, are you scared of this place?
不  我才不怕这里
No. Scared of nothing here.
只不过...
It's just that...
有些地方就跟人一样
you know, some places are like people.
有些有闪灵能力  有些没有
Some shine and some don't.
我觉得可以说眺望酒店
I guess you could say the Overlook Hotel
就有类似于闪灵的能力
has something about it that's like shining.
这里有不好的东西吗
Is there something bad here?
其实  博士  当某件事发生之后
You know, Doc, when something happens...
它会在身后留下踪迹
it can leave a trace of itself behind.
就比如说
Say, like...
有人烤焦了吐司
if someone burns toast.
也许某些事发生后会留下其他类型的踪迹
Maybe things that happen leave other kind of traces behind.
不是人人都能注意得到的踪迹
Not things that anyone can notice.
只有拥有闪灵能力的人才能看到的踪迹
But things that people who shine can see.
就像他们能看见尚未发生的事情一样
Just like they can see things that haven't happened yet...
有时他们也能看见很久以前发生的事
sometimes they can see things that happened a long time ago.
我觉得就这家酒店
I think a lot of things happened right here
多年来肯定发生过很多事
in this particular hotel over the years.
并不全是好事
And not all of them was good.
237号房是怎么回事
What about room 237?
237号房
Room 237?
你害怕237号房  不是吗
You're scared of room 237, ain't you?
不  我没有
No, I ain't.
哈洛兰先生  237号房里有什么
Mr. Hallorann, what is in room 237?
什么都没有
Nothing.
237号房里什么都没有
There ain't nothing in room 237.
但反正你也不需要进去做什么事
But you ain't got no business going in there anyway.
所以别进去
So stay out.
你明白吗  别进去
You understand? Stay out!
一个月后
早  亲爱的
Good morning, hon.
你的早餐好了
Your breakfast is ready.
几点了
What time is it?
大概11点半
It's about 11:30.
11点半  老天啊
Eleven-thirty, Jesus.
我们熬夜熬得太晚了
I guess we've been staying up too late.
我知道
I know it.
我按你的喜好煎了蛋  只煎一面
I made them just the way you like them, sunny-side up.
真棒
Nice.
外面很漂亮
It's really pretty outside.
你吃完早餐之后  带我出去散散步怎么样
How about taking me for a walk after you finish your breakfast?
我应该先试着写点东西
I suppose I ought to try to do some writing first.
有灵感了吗
Any ideas yet?
思如泉涌
Lots of ideas.
可惜都算不上好
No good ones.
你会想到好点子的
Well, something will come.
关键是你得适应每天都写作的习惯
It's just a matter of settling into the habit of writing every day.
是啊  那就是关键
Yep. That's all it is.
这里真的很好  对吧
It's really nice up here, isn't it?
我爱这里
I love it.
真的很爱
I really do.
我从来没这么开心自在过
I've never been this happy or comfortable anywhere.
你这么快就适应了这大房子  真好
It's amazing how fast you get used to such a big place.
我跟你说  我们刚来的时候
I tell you, when we first came up here,
我还觉得这里有点吓人
I thought it was kind of scary.
我立马就爱上了这里
I fell in love with it right away.
我过来面试的时候
When I came up here for my interview,
就好像以前来过这里
it was as though I'd been here before.
我们都有过似曾相识的感觉
I mean, we all have moments of déjà vu,
但这也太离奇了
but this was ridiculous.
就好像我知道
It was almost as though I knew
每个角落会有什么一样
what was going to be around every corner.
输的人要打扫全美国  怎么样
The loser has to keep America clean. How's that?
-好啊  -你输定了
- All right. - And you're going to lose.
我要抓到你了  你最好跑快点
And I'm going to get you. You'd better run fast!
小心
Look out!
我要追上来了  知道吗
I'm coming in close. All right?
输的人要把美国打扫干净
Loser has to keep America clean.
眺望迷宫
-不要啊  -要把美国打扫干净
- Oh, no! - Keep America clean.
好吧
Okay.
丹尼  你赢了
Danny, you win.
剩下的路我们就走走吧
Let's take the rest of this walking.
-好  -真累
- Okay. - Whew.
手给我
Give me your hand.
很漂亮对吧
Isn't it beautiful?
是啊
Yeah.
死路
Dead end.
我们成功了
Woo, we made it.
-很漂亮对吧  -是啊
- Isn't it beautiful? - Yeah.
真漂亮
It's so pretty.
是啊
Yeah.
我没想到会有这么大  你呢
I didn't think it was going to be this big. Did you?
没想到
Nope.
星期二
卢瑟福德因为1968年的枪击案
Rutherford was serving a life sentence...
被判处无期徒刑
for his conviction in the 1968 shooting.
警方仍在乌雷附近的山中
And the search continues in the mountains near Uray today
搜寻那位失踪的阿斯彭女子
for that missing Aspen woman.
24岁的苏珊·罗伯森已失踪十天
Twenty-four-year-old Susan Robertson has been missing 10 days.
她在和丈夫外出打猎时失踪
She disappeared while on a hunting trip with her husband.
目前的天气很好
They have good weather right now,
但如果预计的暴风雪明日到达
but they may have to call off the search...
他们可能不得不叫停搜索
if a predicted snowstorm moves in tomorrow.
但是今天丹佛的天气这么好
But it's so beautiful in Denver today,
很难想象马上就会有暴风雪
it's hard to believe a snowstorm could be that close.
我知道  我也想出去沐浴阳光
I know. I want to go outside and lie in the sun.
但是我们的北面和西面都在下雪  很冷
Yet to our north, to our west, it is snowing and cold.
此刻  暴风雪正朝着科罗拉多州袭来
And it's moving right here towards Colorado as we talk.
真是难以置信
It's incredible.
你好  亲爱的
Hi, hon.
怎么样了
How's it going?
挺好的
Fine.
今天写了很多吗
Get a lot written today?
是的
Yes.
话说  天气预报说今晚会下雪
Hey, the weather forecast said it's going to snow tonight.
那你要我怎样
What do you want me to do about it?
别这样  亲爱的
Come on, hon.
别这么暴躁
Don't be so grouchy.
我没有
I'm not...
暴躁
being grouchy.
我就是想完成作品
I just want to finish my work.
好的  我明白
Okay. I understand.
我一会儿再给你带几个三明治过来
I'll come back later on with a couple of sandwiches for you and...
可能你就会让我看一点了
maybe you'll let me read something then.
温蒂
Wendy,
我跟你解释一下
let me explain something to you.
只要你进来  打扰我
Whenever you come in here and interrupt me,
你就让我没法集中注意力
you're breaking my concentration.
你在让我分心
You're distracting me,
我要花很久才能回到之前的状态
and it will then take me time to get back to where I was.
懂了吗
Understand?
懂了
Yeah.
很好
Fine.
我们要定一条新规矩
Now we're going to make a new rule.
只要我在这里
Whenever I'm in here
你听见我在打字
and you hear me typing,
或者你没听见我打字
or whether you don't hear me typing,
或者不管你听见我在这里面做什么
or whatever the fuck you hear me doing in here,
只要我在这里  就意味着我在工作
when I'm in here, that means I am working,
也意味着不要进来
that means don't come in.
这个你能做到吗
Now, do you think you can handle that?
可以
Yeah.
很好
Fine.
不如你就从现在开始  马上滚远点
Why don't you start right now and get the fuck out of here?
好吧
Okay.
星期四
你够了
All right, you!
我知道你还有雪球
I know you've got more.
没打中
Missed!
没雪球了
Don't have!
不公平了
No fair anymore.
星期六
别啊
Oh, no.
我就知道
I knew it.
KDK12号呼叫KDK1号
This is KDK 12 calling KDK 1.
KDK 12 to KDK 1.
我是KDK1号  我们听到了  完毕
This is KDK 1. We're receiving you. Over.
你好  我是眺望酒店的温蒂·托伦斯
Hi, this is Wendy Torrance at the Overlook Hotel.
你好  你们在山上如何  完毕
Hi, how are you folks getting on up there? Over.
我们挺好的
We're just fine.
但是我们的电话似乎坏了
But our telephones don't seem to be doing too well.
有没有可能是电话线断了  完毕
Are the lines down, by any chance? Over.
没错  因为暴雪不少电话线都断了  完毕
Yes, quite a few of them are down due to the storm. Over.
有可能尽快修好吗  完毕
Any chance of them being repaired soon? Over.
我也不想这么说
Well, I wouldn't like to say.
多数年份里  都要到春天才能修好  完毕
Most winters they stay that way until spring. Over.
天啊  这暴风雪真的很强对吧  完毕
Boy, this storm is really something, isn't it? Over.
没错  这是近几年来最强的一次
Yes. It's one of the worst we've had for years.
有别的要帮忙的吗  托伦斯夫人  完毕
Is there anything else we can do for you, Mrs. Torrance? Over.
我觉得没了  完毕
I suppose not. Over.
如果你们在山上有麻烦  就跟我们联系
If you folks have any problems up there, just give us a call.
另外  托伦斯夫人
And, Mrs. Torrance?
我觉得你最好
I think it might be a good idea
一直把无线电开着  完毕
if you leave your radio on all the time now. Over.
好的  那我们就开着
Okay. We'll do that.
跟你通话很愉快
It was real nice talking to you.
再见  完毕  退出
Bye. Over and out.
你好  丹尼
Hello, Danny.
来和我们一起玩吧
Come and play with us.
来和我们一起玩吧  丹尼
Come and play with us, Danny.
永远
For ever...
and ever...
永远
and ever.
托尼
Tony,
我害怕
I'm scared.
记住哈洛兰先生说的话
Remember what Mr. Hallorann said.
这就像书里的插画  丹尼
It's just like pictures in a book, Danny.
这不是真的
It isn't real.
星期一
我给你些钱吧
Please let me give you some money.
我没想要钱
I wouldn't think of it.
那我该如何报答你
Well, how can I repay you?
没事的  真的
It's okay. Really.
我去煮一点咖啡
Well, I'm going to have some coffee.
你想喝吗
Would you like some?
好啊
Sure.
太好了  坐下
Great. Sit down.
好吃的甜甜圈  请自便
Ooh, these marvellous doughnuts. Help yourself.
-咖啡过几分钟就好  -妈妈
- Coffee will be ready in a few minutes. - Mom?
怎么了
Yeah?
我可以去我的房间拿消防车吗
Can I go up to my room and get my fire-engine?
现在不行  爸爸在睡觉
Not right now. Daddy's asleep.
我不会发出声音的
I won't make any noise.
别闹  博士
Come on, Doc.
他几个小时之前才去睡觉
He only went to bed a few hours ago.
你不能等他起来再拿吗
Can't you wait till later?
我不会发出声音的  我保证会踮着脚走
I won't make a sound. I promise I'll tiptoe.
那好吧
Well, all right.
不过千万别发出声音
But really don't make a sound.
我不会的  妈妈
I won't, Mom.
你拿到了就马上回来
Make sure you come right back,
因为我很快要做午餐了
because I'm going to make lunch soon.
-知道了吗  -知道了  妈妈
- Okay? - Okay, Mom.
我可以去我的房间拿消防车吗
Can I go to my room and get my fire-engine?
先到这里来一下
Come here for a minute first.
你还好吗  博士
How's it going, Doc?
挺好的
Okay.
玩得开心吗
Having a good time?
开心  爸爸
Yes, Dad.
那就好
Good.
我希望你能开心
I want you to have a good time.
我很开心  爸爸
I am, Dad.
爸爸
Dad?
怎么了
Yes?
你不舒服吗
Do you feel bad?
没有
No.
我就是有点累
I'm just a little bit tired.
那你为什么不睡觉
Then why don't you go to sleep?
我不能睡
I can't.
我还有很多活要干
I got too much to do.
爸爸
Dad?
怎么了
Yes?
你喜欢这个酒店吗
Do you like this hotel?
是啊
Yes.
我喜欢
I do.
我很爱它
I love it.
你不喜欢吗
Don't you?
喜欢吧
I guess so.
那就好
Good.
我希望你喜欢这里
I want you to like it here.
我希望我们可以永远待在这里
I wish we could stay here forever...
永远
and ever...
and ever.
爸爸
Dad?
怎么了
What?
你永远不会伤害我和妈妈  对吧
You would never hurt Mommy or me, would you?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你妈妈跟你那么说过吗
Did your mother ever say that to you?
说我会伤害你们吗
That I would hurt you?
没有  爸爸
No, Dad.
你确定吗
You sure?
是的  爸爸
Yes, Dad.
我爱你  丹尼
I love you, Danny.
我爱你胜过全世界任何东西
I love you more than anything else in the whole world,
我绝不会伤害你
and I would never do anything to hurt you,
绝对不会
never.
你知道的  对吧
You know that, don't you?
是的  爸爸
Yes, Dad.
很好
Good.
星期三
妈妈
Mom?
妈妈  你在里面吗
Mom, are you in there?
危险  高压电
杰克
Jack!
杰克  杰克
Jack? Jack!
杰克
Jack!
出什么事了
What happened?
亲爱的
Honey...
出什么事了
What's wrong?
杰克
Jack?
我做了一个这辈子最可怕的噩梦
I had the most terrible nightmare I ever had.
-最可怕的噩梦  -没事了  已经没事了
- It was the most horrible dream. - It's okay, it's okay now.
真的
Really.
我梦到我...
I dreamed that I...
杀了你和丹尼
that I killed you and Danny.
但我不只是杀死了你们
But I didn't just kill you.
我还将你们剁成碎块
I cut you up into little pieces.
我的天
My God.
我肯定是疯了
I must be losing my mind.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's going to be all right.
来  先起来
Come on. Let's get up off the floor.
没事了  来  坐好
It's okay. There. Now sit up.
没事了
It's okay.
丹尼
Danny!
这里没事
Everything's okay!
你先回自己房间玩一会儿
Just go play in your room for a while.
你爸爸只是有点头疼
Your dad's just got a headache.
丹尼  听我的话  回自己房间玩去
Danny, mind what I say. Go play in your room.
亲爱的  我先把他带走
Honey, let me just go get him out of here.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
丹尼
Danny.
你为什么不听我的话
Why don't you mind me?
丹尼
Danny.
我的天
Oh, my God.
丹尼  你的脖子怎么了
Danny, what happened to your neck?
是你弄伤了他
You did this to him...
是不是
didn't you?!
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
是你弄伤了他
You did this to him!
是不是
Didn't you?!
你怎么能这样
How could you?!
金色舞厅
老天  要能喝杯酒我愿意付出一切
God! I'd give anything for a drink.
我愿意出卖灵魂
I'd give my goddamn soul...
换一杯啤酒
for just a glass of beer.
嗨  劳埃德
Hi, Lloyd.
今晚有些无聊  不是吗
A little slow tonight, isn't it?
是的  托伦斯先生
Yes, it is, Mr. Torrance.
您要喝什么
What will it be?
我很高兴你问出了这句话  劳埃德
I'm awfully glad you asked me that, Lloyd...
因为我钱包里刚好有两张二十美元
because I just happen to have two twenties
和两张十美元的钞票
and two tens right here in my wallet.
我本来还担心明年四月前都花不出去了
I was afraid they were going to be there until next April.
你听好
So here's what:
给我一瓶波旁酒
You slip me a bottle of bourbon...
一个玻璃杯和一些冰
A little glass and some ice.
你能做到的  对吗  劳埃德
You can do that, can't you, Lloyd?
你不会忙不过来的  对吗
You're not too busy, are you?
不会  先生  我一点也不忙
No, sir. I'm not busy at all.
好样的
Good man.
你给我倒一杯  我就喝光一杯  劳埃德
You set them up and I'll knock them back, Lloyd,
一杯接一杯
one by one.
白人的负担  劳埃德  伙计
White man's burden, Lloyd, my man.
白人的负担
White man's burden.
劳埃德
Say, Lloyd...
我暂时囊中羞涩
it seems I'm temporarily light.
我在这里的信用怎么样
How's my credit in this joint, anyway?
您的信用没问题  托伦斯先生
Your credit's fine, Mr. Torrance.
那太好了
That's swell.
我喜欢你  劳埃德
I like you, Lloyd.
我一直很喜欢你
I always liked you.
你一直是最优秀的
You were always the best of them.
从廷巴克图到缅因州的波特兰  最优秀的酒保
Best goddamned bartender from Timbuktu to Portland, Maine.
或者是俄勒冈州的波特兰
Or Portland, Oregon, for that matter.
谢谢您这么说
Thank you for saying so.
敬我戒酒的这悲惨的五个月
Here's to five miserable months on the wagon
以及它给我造成的无法弥补的伤害
and all the irreparable harm that it's caused me.
您过得还好吗  托伦斯先生
How are things going, Mr. Torrance?
不是很好  劳埃德
Things could be better, Lloyd.
非常不好
Things could be a whole lot better.
我希望不是什么大事
I hope it's nothing serious.
不
No.
不是大事
Nothing serious.
不过是跟楼上那个"精子银行"发生了点口角
Just a little problem with the old sperm bank upstairs.
不过我都能应付  劳埃德
Nothing I can't handle, though, Lloyd.
谢了
Thanks.
女人啊
Women.
受不了她们
Can't live with them
却又少不了她们
can't live without them.
至理名言  劳埃德
Words of wisdom, Lloyd.
至理名言
Words of wisdom.
我根本没打过他  该死的
I never laid a hand on him, goddamn it.
我没有
I didn't.
我都舍不得碰他那小脑袋上的一根头发
I wouldn't touch one hair on his goddamn little head.
我爱那个小混蛋
I love the little son of a bitch.
我愿意为他做任何事
I'd do anything for him.
真他妈是任何事
Any fucking thing for him.
但那个贱人
But that bitch!
只要我还活着
As long as I live...
她就不会让我忘记以前的事
she'll never let me forget what happened.
我确实伤过他一次  行了吧
I did hurt him once, okay?
那是个意外
It was an accident.
我完全是无意的
Completely unintentional.
那可能发生在任何人身上
It could have happened to anybody.
那已经是他妈三年前的事了
And it was three goddamn years ago!
那个小鬼把我的稿子丢得满地都是
The little fucker had thrown all my papers all over the floor.
我只是想把他拉起来
All I tried to do was pull him up.
稍微丧失了一下肌肉协调能力
A momentary loss of muscular coordination.
我是指...
I mean...
多用了那么一点点力气
A few extra foot-pounds of energy...
就那一秒  那一秒
per second, per second.
杰克
Jack!
Oh, Jack.
谢天谢地你在这
Thank God you're here.
杰克
Jack.
酒店里除了我们还有其他人
There's someone else in the hotel with us.
某间房里有个疯女人
There's a crazy woman in one of the rooms.
她想勒死丹尼
She tried to strangle Danny.
你他妈疯了吗
Are you out of your fucking mind?
不是
No.
是真的  真的
It's the truth! Really.
我发誓  是丹尼告诉我的
I swear it. Danny told me.
他跑到某间卧室里
He went up into one of the bedrooms.
房门开着  他看到浴缸里有个疯女人
The door was open, and he saw this crazy woman in the bathtub.
她想勒死他
She tried to strangle him!
是哪间房
Which room was it?
迈阿密十频道
From Channel 10 in Miami...
欢迎收看《新闻观察》
this is Newswatch
由格伦·林克  安·毕肖普
with Glenn Rinker, Ann Bishop,
及《新闻观察》获奖制作团队为您呈现
and the award-winning Newswatch team.
晚上好  我是十频道《新闻观察》的格伦·林克
Good evening. I'm Glenn Rinker, Newswatch Ten.
迈阿密冬季热浪刷新纪录  持续闷热难耐
While Miami continues to swelter in a record winter heatwave
气温上升到90多华氏度左右
bringing temperatures to the mid and upper nineties,
而中部和落基山脉覆盖的各州则被大雪覆盖
the Central and Rocky Mountain States are buried in snow.
在科罗拉多州
In Colorado,
今晚不过短短数小时  降雪量就达10英寸
10 inches of snow has fallen in just a few hours tonight.
在落基山脉通行变成几乎不可能的事了
Travel in the Rockies is almost impossible.
机场关闭  成千上万名旅客滞留
Airports are shut down, stranding thousands of passengers.
高速公路被积雪堵住
Highways are blocked by snowdrifts.
铁轨冻结
Railroad tracks are frozen.
科罗拉多州官方告知《新闻观察》
Officials in Colorado tell Newswatch...
至少已有三人因暴露在寒风中死亡
at least three have been killed by exposure to freezing winds.
科罗拉多州州长预计将在明天
The governor of Colorado is expected tomorrow
宣布天气紧急状况
to declare a weather emergency.
国民警卫队可能会被派遣
The National Guard might be called out...
去清空街道和道路
to clear streets and roads.
天气预报员预测今夜至明天
Weather forecasters predict more snow...
会有更多降雪及强风
and heavy winds tonight and tomorrow...
气温将会降到零华氏度以下
with temperatures dropping well below zero.
佛罗里达南部这里  我们的问题正相反
Back here in south Florida, we've got the opposite problem.
温度和湿度预计会上升
The heat and humidity are supposed to climb.
本地海滩将人满为患
Local beaches should be jammed.
我们的天气专家沃特·克罗莱斯
Our weather expert, Walter Cronice...
稍后将在《新闻观察》中带来本地天气预报
will have the local forecast later on Newswatch.
237号房
很抱歉  您拨打的电话无法接通
We're sorry. Your call cannot be completed as dialed.
如需要协助  请打给接线员
If you need assistance, please call the operator.
杰克
Jack?
没错  是我
Yes, it's me.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你找到什么了吗
Did you find anything?
没有  什么都没有
No. Nothing at all.
我什么都没看到
I didn't see one goddamn thing.
你去的是丹尼说的房间吗  237号房
You went into the room Danny said? To 237?
是的  我去了
Yes, I did.
你什么都没看到吗
And you didn't see anything at all?
什么都没有
Absolutely nothing.
他怎么样了
How is he?
他还在睡
He's still asleep.
那就好
Good.
他肯定明天早上就会恢复正常了
I'm sure he'll be himself again in the morning.
你确定你没找错房间吗
Are you sure it was the right room?
我是说  或许是丹尼记错了
I mean, maybe Danny made a mistake.
他去的肯定是那间房
He must have gone in that room.
房门开着  灯也开着
The door was open, the lights were on.
我只是不明白
I just don't understand it.
他脖子上的淤伤是怎么回事
What about those bruises on his neck?
肯定是有人掐的
Somebody did that to him.
我想...
I think...
是他自己掐的
he did it to himself.
不
No.
那不可能
That's not possible.
温蒂
Wendy...
一旦我们排除他的说法
once you rule out his version of what happened...
事情就没有其他解释了
there is no other explanation.
不是吗
Is there?
这和我们到这里来之前
It wouldn't be that different from the episode...
他的那次发作差不多
that he had before we came up here.
不是吗
Would it?
杰克
Oh, Jack.
无论解释是什么
Whatever the explanation is...
红朗姆
我觉得我们...
I think we...
得带丹尼离开这里
have to get Danny out of here.
带他离开这里
Get him out of here?
是的
Yes.
你是说直接离开这家酒店
You mean just leave the hotel?
是的
Yes.
你他妈就会没事找事
It is so fucking typical of you to create a problem like this
我好不容易有机会能做出点成果
when I finally have a chance to accomplish something!
我好不容易一心扑在写作上
When I'm really into my work!
如果我现在回博尔德
I could really write my own ticket
就可以随心所欲了  是吗
if I went back to Boulder now, couldn't I?
给车道铲雪  在洗车场打工
Shoveling out driveways, work in a car wash.
-你觉得这些工作很好是吗  -杰克
- Any of that appeal to you? - Jack...
温蒂  我一直都在纵容你搞砸我的人生
Wendy, I have let you fuck up my life so far,
但我绝不允许你搞砸我这次的机会
but I am not going to let you fuck this up.
晚上好  这里是林业局
Good evening. Forest Service.
你好  我叫迪克·哈洛兰
Hello, my name is Dick Hallorann.
我是眺望酒店的厨师长
I'm the head chef up at the Overlook Hotel.
晚上好  哈洛兰先生  请问有什么事吗
Good evening, Mr. Hallorann. What can I do for you?
先生  我一直想打个紧急电话去酒店
Sir, I've been trying to make an urgent phone call up there,
但接线员说电话线路都瘫痪了
but the operator said that the phone lines are down.
是啊  恐怕这附近的许多电话线路
Yeah, I'm afraid a lot of lines around here are down
都因为暴风雪断掉了
due to the storm.
是这样的  先生  我也不想麻烦你
Well, look sir, I hate to put you through any trouble,
但酒店里住着一家人  带着个小孩
but there's a family up there all by themselves with a young kid,
现在又来了这么大的暴风雪
and with this storm and everything...
能不能拜托你用无线电联系一下他们
I'd sure appreciate it if you'd give them a call on your radio
确保没出什么事
just to see if everything's okay.
我很乐意帮这个忙  先生
I'll be glad to do that, sir.
你等20分钟后再打过来吧
Why don't you call me back in about 20 minutes?
非常感谢你  我会的
Thank you very much. I'll do that.
那先这样  先生
All right, sir.
晚上好  托伦斯先生
Good evening, Mr. Torrance.
晚上好
Good evening.
嗨  劳埃德
Hi, Lloyd.
我离开了一阵  不过现在回来了
I've been away, but now I'm back.
晚上好  托伦斯先生
Good evening, Mr. Torrance.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
回来的感觉真好  劳埃德
It's good to be back, Lloyd.
您想喝点什么  先生
What'll it be, sir?
解醉酒
Hair of the dog that bit me.
波旁威士忌加冰块
Bourbon on the rocks.
就它了
That'll do her.
不用给钱  托伦斯先生
No charge to you, Mr. Torrance.
不要钱
No charge?
你的钱在这里用不上
Your money's no good here.
免费赠送
Orders from the house.
喝吧  托伦斯先生
Drink up, Mr. Torrance.
我这人喜欢搞清楚是谁在请客  劳埃德
I'm the kind of man likes to know who's buying their drinks, Lloyd.
您不用操心这事  托伦斯先生
It's not a matter that concerns you, Mr. Torrance.
至少现在不用
At least, not at this point.
那就听你的  劳埃德
Anything you say, Lloyd.
就听你的
Anything you say.
天呐  天呐  非常抱歉  先生
Oh, dear! Oh, dear! I'm so sorry, sir.
我的天呐
Oh, dear. Oh, dear.
我把您的夹克衫弄脏了  先生
I've made an awful mess of your jacket, sir.
没关系  我有很多件夹克衫
Oh, that's all right. I've got plenty of jackets.
因为这是蛋黄酒  先生  所以会留下污渍
I'm afraid it's advocaat, sir. It tends to stain.
蛋黄酒吗
Advocaat, is it?
是的  先生  我觉得最好的办法
Yes, sir. Look, I think the best thing
就是您跟我一起去卫生间清理  先生
is to come along to the gentlemen's room, sir,
我们可以用水擦掉  先生
and we'll get some water to it, sir.
看样子你的衣服上也被溅到了
Looks as though you might have got a spot of it on yourself there,
侍者先生
Jeevesy old boy.
不要紧的  先生  您..
That doesn't matter, sir. You...
您才是贵客
You're the important one.
你这么说真是太贴心了
Awfully nice of you to say.
当然了  我还是打算先换掉夹克衫
Of course, I intended to change my jacket this evening
再去参加今晚的高级晚会
before the fish and goose soiree.
太明智了  先生
Very wise, sir. Very wise.
来  我帮你开着门  侍者先生
Here. I'll just hold this for you there, Jeevesy.
谢谢您  先生  谢谢
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
来看看能不能用水擦干净  先生
Now let's see if we can improve this with a little water, sir.
好的  那我就...
All right. I'll just...
把我的波旁威士忌和蛋黄酒放这里
set my bourbon and advocaat down right there.
不会耽误您太多时间  先生
Won't keep you a moment, sir.
好的
Fine.
这里的人都是怎么称呼你的  侍者先生
What do they call you around here, Jeevesy?
格拉迪  先生  德尔波特·格拉迪
Grady, sir. Delbert Grady.
格拉迪
Grady?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
德尔波特·格拉迪
Delbert Grady.
没错  先生
That's right, sir.
格拉迪先生
Mr. Grady...
我们之前是不是在哪里见过
Haven't I seen you somewhere before?
怎么会  先生  我想应该没有
Why, no, sir. I don't believe so.
都擦掉了  先生
It's coming off now, sir.
格拉迪先生
Mr. Grady,
你以前在这里当过管理员吧
weren't you once the caretaker here?
怎么会  先生  恐怕不是
Why, no, sir. I don't believe so.
你结婚了  对吧  格拉迪先生
You a married man, are you, Mr. Grady?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
我有个老婆和两个女儿  先生
I have a wife and two daughters, sir.
那么...
And...
她们现在在哪里
where are they now?
就在这附近吧
They're somewhere around.
此刻我也不太清楚  先生
I'm not quite sure at the moment, sir.
格拉迪先生
Mr. Grady,
你曾经就是这里的管理员
you were the caretaker here.
我认得你
I recognize you.
我在报纸上看过你的照片
I saw your picture in the newspapers.
你...
You...
把你的妻子女儿大卸八块
chopped your wife and daughters up into little bits.
然后
And...
一枪爆头自杀了
and you blew your brains out.
这就奇怪了  先生
That's strange, sir.
我一点印象都没有
I don't have any recollection of that at all.
格拉迪先生
Mr. Grady,
你曾经就是这里的管理员
you were the caretaker here.
抱歉我不敢苟同  先生
I'm sorry to differ with you, sir.
但你...
But you
才是这里现在的管理员
are the caretaker.
你一直都是这里的管理员
You've always been the caretaker.
我很清楚  先生
I should know, sir.
因为我一直都在这里
I've always been here.
你知道吗  托伦斯先生
Did you know, Mr. Torrance,
你儿子...
that your son...
正打算带外人进来搅局
is attempting to bring an outside party into this situation?
你知道吗
Did you know that?
不知道
No.
是真的  托伦斯先生
He is, Mr. Torrance.
谁
Who?
一个黑人
A nigger.
黑人
A nigger?
一个黑人厨师
A nigger cook.
怎么做到
How?
你儿子拥有一种超凡的才能
Your son has a very great talent.
我觉得你还不清楚那究竟有多超凡
I don't think you are aware how great it is,
但他正打算使用这一才能
but he is attempting to use that very talent
违背你的意愿
against your will.
他的确是个任性的孩子
He is a very willful boy.
没错  托伦斯先生
Indeed he is, Mr. Torrance.
一个非常任性的孩子
A very willful boy.
一个非常调皮的孩子
A rather naughty boy,
请恕我大胆直言  先生
if I may be so bold, sir.
是因为他的母亲
It's his mother.
她喜欢胡乱干预
She interferes.
或许该好好跟他们谈谈了
Perhaps they need a good talking-to.
希望你别介意我这么说
If you don't mind my saying so.
或许要采取更严厉的手段
Perhaps a bit more.
我的两个女儿  先生
My girls, sir,
她们一开始毫不关心眺望酒店
they didn't care for the Overlook at first.
其中一个还偷了一盒火柴
One of them actually stole a pack of matches
想要放火烧了这里
and tried to burn it down.
但我纠正了她们  先生
But I corrected them, sir.
当我妻子试图阻止我履行职责时
And when my wife tried to prevent me from doing my duty,
我也纠正了她
I corrected her.
我们有雪地车
We have the Snowcat.
如果天气放晴
If the weather breaks,
我们也许能开雪地车下山
we might just be able to get down the mountain in that.
我可以先跟护林员打个电话
I could call the forest rangers first
告诉他们我们要来了
and then tell them that we're coming
如果我们遇到了麻烦  他们还能来找我们
so that they could start searching for us, in case we didn't make it.
如果杰克不肯跟我们走
And if Jack won't come with us,
直接告诉他我们自己走就行了
we'll just have to tell him that we're going by ourselves.
只能这样了
That's all there is to it.
红朗姆
Redrum.
红朗姆  红朗姆
Redrum. Redrum.
-丹尼  -红朗姆
- Danny? - Redrum.
红朗姆  红朗姆
Redrum. Redrum.
-红朗姆  -丹尼  怎么了  宝贝
- Redrum. - Danny, what's the matter, hon?
红朗姆
Redrum!
你是做噩梦了吗
Are you having a bad dream?
丹尼
Danny?
宝贝
Hon?
丹尼不在这里  托伦斯夫人
Danny's not here, Mrs. Torrance.
好了  宝贝
Come on, hon.
快醒过来
Wake up.
你只是做了个噩梦
You just had a bad dream.
一切都没事
Everything's okay.
丹尼醒不过来  托伦斯夫人
Danny can't wake up, Mrs. Torrance.
丹尼
Danny.
醒醒
Wake up!
快啊
Come on.
快醒醒
Right now.
醒醒啊
Wake up!
丹尼已经走了  托伦斯夫人
Danny's gone away, Mrs. Torrance.
丹尼
Danny.
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
能收到吗
Are you receiving me?
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
能听到吗
Do you read me?
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
能收到吗
Are you receiving me?
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
能听到吗
Do you read me?
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号
This is KDK 1 calling KDK 12.
KDK1号呼叫KDK12号  能收到...
KDK 1 calling KDK 12. Are you receiv-
晚上好  这里是林业局
Good evening. Forest service.
你好  又是我  迪克·哈洛兰
Hello. This is Dick Hallorann again.
我之前打过电话  询问眺望酒店的人是否平安
I called a while ago about the folks at the Overlook Hotel.
对  没错
Oh, yeah.
我们尝试用无线电联系他们好几次
We tried to contact them several times by radio
但他们没回复
but they didn't answer.
也许他们把无线电关了
Maybe they got their radio turned off
或是他们恰好在一个听不到呼叫的地方
or they are in a place where they can't hear it.
如果你希望  我很乐意待会儿再试试
If you'd like, I'd be glad to try again later on.
你真的很好心
That's very nice of you.
我晚点再打给你
I'll call you back later.
再见
Bye.
早上8点
请问一下  女士  我们几点能到丹佛
Pardon me, miss. What time will we get to Denver?
预计8点20到达  先生
We're due to arrive at 8:20, sir.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
德肯汽修店
Durkin's Garage.
我想找莱瑞
Can I speak to Larry?
我就是
Speaking.
你好  莱瑞  我是迪克  迪克·哈洛兰
Hi, Larry. This is Dick. Dick Hallorann.
迪克  你还好吗
Dick! How you doing?
你那里天气如何
How's the weather down there?
我不在佛罗里达  莱瑞
I'm not in Florida, Larry.
我现在在斯台普顿机场给你打电话
I'm calling from Stapleton Airport.
你跑到那里干什么
What the hell are you doing down there?
我刚从迈阿密飞来  今天得赶去眺望酒店
I just got in from Miami. I got to get to the Overlook today.
那边的天气怎么样
What's the weather like there?
城里一直用扫雪机清除路面上的雪
The snowplows are keeping things moving in town...
但山路全被雪封住了
but the mountain roads are blocked.
那我得开雪地车才能上山了
Then I'm going to need a Snowcat to get up there.
你能帮我找一辆吗
Can you fix me up with one?
有什么要紧事  你非得今天上山
What's the big deal about getting there today...
尤其天气还这么糟
especially in this kind of weather?
莱瑞  私下里跟你说
Larry, just between you and me,
看守酒店的那家人
we got a very serious problem with the people
有重大问题
who are taking care of the place.
没想到他们是完全靠不住的混蛋
They turned out to be completely unreliable assholes.
乌尔曼昨晚打给我
Ullman phoned me last night.
叫我上山去酒店一趟
And I'm supposed to go up there
看看是否需要换掉他们
and find out if they have to be replaced.
你过来这里要花多长时间
How long will it take you to get up here?
大约五小时
About five hours.
我会在机场这里租一辆车
I'm going to rent a car here at the airport.
好  迪克  我会帮你准备好的
Okay, Dick, I'll take care of it.
太谢谢你了  莱瑞  感激不尽
Thanks a lot, Larry. I really appreciate that.
不客气  小心驾驶
That's all right. Drive carefully.
各位早上好
Well, good morning to you,
欢迎收听丹佛KHOW63台  我们是哈尔和查理
You're with Hal and Charlie on Radio 63, KHOW, Denver.
查理  今天天气真的糟透了
And Charlie, we have what you call your bad day out there.
现在天降大雪
What you call your heavy snow,
整个丹佛地区都在下大雪
snowing hard throughout the Denver metro area.
很多山路...
Many mountain passes...
狼溪和红山山路都已封闭
Wolf Creek and Red Mountain passes are already closed...
艾森豪威尔隧道也已封闭
and the chain law is in effect right now at the Eisenhower Tunnel.
据新闻部门刚刚的消息
I guess as we've just heard from the news forecast,
只有寥寥几个航班在斯台普顿机场降落
only a few flights are landing at Stapleton Airport.
暴风雪这么早就开始侵袭
and, with these early storms like this,
我估计一小时内整个机场都会关闭
I guess the entire airport will probably be closed within the hour.
没错  他们没有做好应对准备
Yeah, they're just not prepared.
暴风雪会持续一整天
The storm will continue through the day
国家气象局
and the National Weather Service
已向市区外围所有地区的
has declared a stockman's and traveler's advisory
畜牧业者和旅客发布警报
for all areas outlying the Denver metro region.
把牛都赶进棚里
Get the cows in the barn.
没错  很多商业...
There you go.  Many businesses...
宝贝
Hon?
你先听我说  好吗
Listen to me for a minute, will you?
我要去找爸爸谈一下
I'm just going to go and talk to Daddy for a few minutes...
我很快就回来
and I'll be right back.
我要你乖乖待在这里
I want you to just stay here...
看卡通片  好吗
and watch your cartoons, okay?
好吗  宝贝
Okay, hon?
好的  托伦斯夫人
Yes, Mrs. Torrance.
好了
All right.
我大概五分钟后就回来
I'll- I'll be back in just about five minutes.
我会把门锁上
I'm going to lock the door behind me.
杰克
Jack?
只工作不玩乐让杰克沉闷无趣
只工作不玩乐让杰克沉闷无趣.
你觉得怎么样
How do you like it?
杰克
Jack.
你觉得怎么样
How do you like it?
你下来这里做什么
What are you doing down here?
我只是...
I just...
想...
wanted...
跟你谈谈
to talk to you.
好啊
Okay.
来谈吧
Let's talk.
你想谈什么
What do you want to talk about?
我...
I...
我不记得了
I can't really remember.
你不记得了
You can't remember.
是啊  我不记得了
No... I can't.
也许是跟丹尼有关
Maybe it was about Danny?
也许跟他有关
Maybe it was about him.
我觉得我们应该商量下丹尼的事
I think we should discuss Danny.
红朗姆
我觉得...
I think...
我们该商量下该如何处置他
we should discuss what should be done with him.
该如何处置他呢
What should be done with him?
我不知道
I don't know.
我认为这不是真话
I don't think that's true.
我认为你已经有明确的想法
I think you have some very definite ideas...
该如何处置丹尼
about what should be done with Danny.
我想知道你的想法
And I'd like to know what they are.
我...
Well, I...
我觉得或许该带他去看医生
I think maybe he should be taken to a doctor.
你觉得"或许"该带他去看医生
You think "maybe" he should be taken to a doctor?
是的
Yes.
你觉得"或许"该何时带他去看医生呢
When do you think "maybe" he should be taken to a doctor?
尽快
As soon as possible?
"尽快"
"As soon as possible?"
杰克
Jack.
求求你
Please.
你认为他的健康可能出现问题了
You believe his health might be at stake.
是的
Yes.
你很担心他
And you are concerned about him.
是的
Yes.
那你担心我吗
And are you concerned about me?
我当然担心你了
Of course I am.
你当然担心我了
Of course you are!
你有没有考虑过我的责任
Have you ever thought about my responsibilities?
杰克  你在说什么
Oh, Jack, what are you talking about?
你有没有那么一刻
Have you ever had a single moment's
考虑过我的责任
thought about my responsibilities?
你有没有那么一瞬间
Have you ever thought for a single solitary moment
考虑过我对我雇主的责任
about my responsibilities to my employers?!
你有没有想过
Has it ever occurred to you
我答应了照看这家酒店直到5月1号
that I have agreed to look after the hotel until May 1st?
难道你丝毫不在意
Does it matter to you at all
酒店老板们对我的信心和信任吗
that the owners have placed their complete confidence and trust in me
我还签了一份协议书
and that I have signed a letter of agreement.
一份合同
A contract
代表我接受了这份责任
in which I've accepted that responsibility?
你到底知不知道
Do you have the slightest idea
什么是做人的道德准则  你知道吗
what a moral and ethical principal is? Do you?!
你有没有想过  如果我未能履行自己的职责
Has it ever occurred to you what would happen to my future
那会对我的未来造成什么影响
if I fail to live up to my responsibilities?
你到底有没有想过  有没有
Has it ever occurred to you? Has it?!
离我远点
Stay away from me!
为什么
Why?
我只想回我的房间
I just want to go back to my room.
为什么
Why?
我很混乱
I'm very confused.
我需要个机会好好想清楚
And I just need a chance to think things over.
你已经有一辈子的时间可以好好想清楚
You've had your whole fucking life to think things over!
现在再多想区区几分钟又有什么用
What good's a few minutes more going to do you now?
离我远点
Stay away from me!
求你了
Please!
别伤害我
Don't hurt me.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not going to hurt you.
离我远点
Stay away from me!
-温蒂  -走开
- Wendy. - Stay away!
亲爱的
Darling.
我的生命之光
Light of my life.
我是不会伤害你的
I'm not going to hurt you.
你没让我说完
You didn't let me finish my sentence.
我说  "我不会伤害你的"
I said, "I'm not going to hurt you. "
我只会把你的脑袋砸烂
I'm just going to bash your brains in.
我会把你打得脑浆四溅
I'm going to bash them right the fuck in.
别过来
Stay away from me!
别伤害我
Don't hurt me!
我不会伤害你的
I'm not going to hurt you.
离我远点
Stay away from me!
别过来
Stay away!
求你了
Please!
别再挥球棒了
Stop swinging the bat.
离我远点
Stay away from me.
把球棒放下  温蒂
Put that bat down, Wendy.
停下
Stop it!
温蒂
Wendy.
把球棒给我
Give me the bat.
求你了
Please!
-离我远点  -把球棒给我
- Stay away! - Give me the bat.
停下
Stop it!
-把球棒给我  -杰克
- Give me the bat. - Jack.
-离我远点  -别挥球棒了
- Stay away from me. - Stop swinging the bat.
停下吧
Please stop!
把球棒给我
Give me the bat.
-离我远点  -温蒂
- Stay away from me. - Wendy.
-停下  -把球棒给我
- Stop it! - Give me the bat.
-离我远点  -把球棒给我
- Stay away! - Give me the bat.
该死的
Goddamn-!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
等等
Wait a minute.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
等等
Wait a minute!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
把门打开
Open the door!
该死的
Goddamn it!
放我出去  把该死的门打开
Let me out of here! Open the goddamn door!
温蒂  听着
Wendy, listen.
放我出去  整件事我就不追究了
Let me out and I'll forget the whole goddamn thing.
就像从没发生过一样
It'll be just like nothing ever happened.
温蒂  宝贝
Wendy. Baby.
我觉得你把我的头伤得很重
I think you hurt my head real bad.
我头晕
I'm dizzy.
我需要看医生
I need a doctor.
亲爱的
Honey.
别把我丢在这
Don't leave me in here.
我要走了
I'm going to go now.
我打算拼尽全力...
I'm going to try to ...
带丹尼回萨德温德镇
get Danny down the Sidewinder...
坐雪地车走
in the Snowcat today.
我会带个医生回来
I'll bring back a doctor.
温蒂
Wendy.
我要走了
I'm going to go now.
温蒂
Wendy.
怎么了
Yes?
有个巨大的惊喜在等着你
You've got a big surprise coming to you.
你休想去任何地方
You're not going anywhere.
去检查下雪地车和无线电
Go check out the Snowcat and the radio,
你就会明白我的意思了
and you'll see what I mean.
去看看吧
Go check it out.
Go check it out!
去看看吧
Go check it out.
下午4点
温蒂
Wendy?
我是格拉迪  托伦斯先生
It's Grady, Mr. Torrance.
德尔波特·格拉迪
Delbert Grady.
格拉迪
Grady?
Grady.
格拉迪  那个...
Grady, uh...
你好  格拉迪
Hello, Grady.
托伦斯先生
Mr. Torrance...
看来你没能完成...
I see you can hardly have taken care of the...
我们讨论过的事宜
business we discussed.
没必要跑来奚落我  格拉迪先生
No need to rub it in, Mr. Grady.
我一出去  就会处理好这个麻烦
I'll deal with that situation as soon as I get out of here.
是吗  托伦斯先生
Will you indeed, Mr. Torrance?
我不是很信
I wonder.
我表示怀疑
I have my doubts.
我和其他人已经开始认定
I, and others, have come to believe...
你的心思不在这上面
that your heart is not in this.
你没有足够的胆识来干这事
That you haven't the belly for it.
再给我一次机会证明自己  格拉迪先生
Just give me one more chance to prove it, Mr. Grady.
我就这一个请求
That's all I ask.
你妻子似乎比我们预想的要强大  托伦斯先生
Your wife appears to be stronger than we imagined, Mr. Torrance.
更加...
Somewhat more...
有智谋
resourceful.
她似乎占了上风
She seems to have got the better of you.
暂时的而已  格拉迪先生
For the moment, Mr. Grady.
暂时的而已
Only for the moment.
恐怕你必须解决这个问题
I fear you will have to deal with this matter...
以最残酷的方式  托伦斯先生
in the harshest possible way, Mr. Torrance.
恐怕...
I fear...
只能这样了
that is the only thing to do.
我非常乐意这么做  格拉迪先生
There's nothing I look forward to with greater pleasure, Mr. Grady.
你保证吗  托伦斯先生
You give your word on that, do you, Mr. Torrance?
我保证
I give you my word.
红朗姆
Redrum.
-红朗姆  -丹尼  停下
- Redrum. - Danny, stop it!
-红朗姆  -丹尼
- Redrum. - Danny!
红朗姆
Redrum.
谋杀
红朗姆
温蒂
Wendy?
我回家了
I'm home.
出来  出来  不管你在哪里
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
丹尼
Danny.
我出不来
I can't get out.
快跑
Run!
快去躲起来
Run and hide!
快跑
Run!
快点
Quick!
小猪小猪  放我进去
Little pigs, little pigs, let me come in.
出自《三只小猪》
痴心妄想  灰狼滚开
Not by the hair on your chinny-chin-chin?
我就吹啊
Then I'll huff...
and I'll puff...
把你的房子吹个底朝天
and I'll blow your house in!
不要
No!
杰克
Jack.
求你了
Please!
别这样
Don't!
求你了
Please.
停下
Stop it!
约翰尼来啦
Here's Johnny!
出自节目
《约翰尼·卡森今夜秀》
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
Anybody here?
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
Anybody here?
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
Anybody here?
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
Anybody here?
丹尼
Danny?
小丹尼
Danny-boy!
丹尼
Danny?
Danny!
丹尼
Danny.
我来了
I'm coming!
我来了  丹
I'm coming, Dan!
丹尼
Danny.
派对很棒吧
Great party, isn't it?
丹尼
Danny.
我来了
I'm coming!!
你跑不掉的
You can't get away!
我就在你后面
I'm right behind you!
丹尼
Danny.
-丹尼  -妈妈
- Danny! - Mommy!
-丹尼  过来  -妈妈
- Danny, come here! - Mommy!
丹尼
Danny.
妈妈
Mommy.
你们在哪...
Where...?
眺望酒店
1921年7月4日国庆舞会